hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
the test automation obstacle with trst
tosa let's look at our next obstacle
which is called the hidden element now
this is an interesting one
uh here it is saying who turned off the
lights click the hidden element and as
you can see there is no way to find out
where that particular element exists
okay so visually I'm not able to see the
element and you will think that it is
impossible to click the hidden element
but in reality I don't need to know
where that particular element is until I
am able to identify that using the tosa
scanner okay so if a tosa is able to
scan that particular element using its
properties and it's able to identify it
on the page then uh no matter if it is
visible actually on the page or not it
can still perform the required operation
okay so let's go ahead and try to scan
this and let's try to find this element
which is currently
hidden so coming back to tosa uh going
back to the modules and here going back
to the folder here let's try and scan
this particular
application okay so here as you can see
we need to do a little bit of digging
around so that we can find this
particular hidden element and uh here in
the filtered items uh you can see that I
cannot see any particular hidden element
so I'm going to increase the filtered
items now okay until I'm able to see all
the elements which are on this HTML page
okay so now coming back here uh we'll
try to find this element by looking at
where uh this particular element may be
present okay and that you can tell by
looking at some of the other elements
okay like this text uh which is the easy
okay so I can see this uh easy element
is right here under this div section so
probably you will have that click
element where we need to click inside
this particular div element okay and uh
going a little further I can see that
there is a click this uh element which
is again like a span element okay and if
I look at its
properties the it has got a ID so that's
very good it can easily identify this
and then uh the tag type is span so it
is a span element right now here um I'm
able to identify this using the ID which
is unique so I don't need to add any
other properties here right so once I'm
able to do this and I'm able to add it
into the module then tosa will be able
to identify this no matter if it is
visible or not visible uh to The Naked
Eyes okay so uh let's go ahead and close
this and let's go ahead and rename the
module
okay so now uh we will go back to our
test cases
section and we will create a new test
case
now okay so now uh let's go ahead and
add the specific module
here and then uh we will look at this
particular test case so what we need to
do we need to just perform a click
operation on this particular element
right and that you know we can do in two
ways we can either use the click
operation or we can also use something
called X which does the same thing okay
so this is all we have to do uh so most
of the work will be done in this
particular case while scanning the
module rather than um designing the test
steps okay so I'll will mark it as
completed and then let's try and run
this in scratchbook
now
okay as you can see it is uh able to
click on that particular hidden element
although we cannot see it still tosa
could identify it and then perform the
click operation on it so that the
obstacle is completed for
us that's all for this particular video
if you have any questions then please
leave it in the comments if you like
this video then please subscribe to our
Channel thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next
video